Stop trying
to put on a tough front around your friends,
Natsuki Subaru!
Your head is just a big, jumbled mess,
and you don't know what to do, right?
You keep getting into situations where
you have to reach out and help,
but both your arms and your head
are too weak to reach far enough,
so you end up just wasting time
frantically flailing around, right?
Do you hear me?
If you hear me, say something!
What the hell was that for?!
You finally lost your temper,
but you forgot to pay
attention to your footing.
That just sums you up perfectly, doesn't it?
Pathetic.
Oh, is that right?!
That's really all the strength you have.
Putting on a tough act for
a girl you love is fine.
And you can play tough for
a girl who likes you, too.
No one would object to that.
But that's as far as it goes!
You know you're not good enough, don't you?
You know you can't reach, don't you?
You want to look good for the
girl you like, don't you?!
You want to be someone the girl who
likes you can be proud of, don't you?!
Then why don't you just
accept someone's help?!
Someone like...
a friend!
I did rely on someone else.
I asked for help.
But it didn't work.
Maybe...
But I don't recall ever
hearing you ask for my help.
N-No, I mean...
My head is just full of knots.
It's full of stuff you wouldn't
believe even if I told you.
I don't even know how to start...
Just start talking.
I'll listen until you finish.
But if I do that—
Didn't I just tell you not
to put on that tough act?!
If you have time to overcomplicate
everything in your head,
then just spit it all out!
Easy for you to say, but I—
Spit out all of those knots!
And when you're done,
just tell me to believe you!
Because I'm your friend, all right?
You might not believe me, but...
Roswaal!
Let's make a bet,
with my wish and yours on the line!
I certainly did not expect to
see you again in this life.
This will be our last showdown.
I'm going to save the Sanctuary
and the mansion in this loop,
whatever it takes.
And I'll bust up every
damn one of your plans!
You want to start over now,
when you have me in check,
and leave behind the one
and only power you have?
Being able to start over and being able
to save them are two different things.
Both you and I were too arrogant.
This power I have isn't even that useful.
If you say this is the last time,
what is it you want from me?
My demand is simple.
If I save both the Sanctuary
and the mansion,
you will throw that book
away and come with me.
I'm going to make Emilia the new ruler,
and I need your help to do it.
Don't be ridiculous.
That suggestion is absolutely warped.
Do you think you would
forgive what I—
If this was about forgiving you,
there's no way in hell I'd ever do that.
But that's for my own heart to worry about.
Nothing deadly has happened yet.
So if I can solve this... Get it?
How can an idea be so convenient?
Hey, I love convenient ideas!
Emilia's gonna do her best
to become the next ruler,
and I'll be by her side to congratulate her.
I want you to be part of the
crowd we'll have around her.
Just so you know, it'll be mandatory.
You expect to fulfill your desire
without letting go of anything?
Not only that, but you say
my involvement is necessary
and insist on including me in
the foundation for the future?
You are aware, are you not, Subaru-kun?
Of what?
Of the sheer greed of that solution.
Your enemy has become the
strongest card in play.
That's still not enough for you?
No matter how you fight it,
you cannot break through this.
With Emilia-sama unable to stand,
the barrier will remain.
The Sanctuary will be covered in snow,
and the mansion will sink
into a bloody tragedy.
Yeah. Should make the sight
of you crying all the better.
I see. You are right.
It isn't a bad idea to lay some
groundwork for the next me.
So can I take that to mean
you agree to the bet?
Well, now that that's settled,
I can get started.
Subaru-kun...
The snow in the Sanctuary and the attack
on the mansion begin in three days.
Do try your hardest to fight it...
and fail miserably.
Say what you want.
Roswaal, put the clown makeup back on, okay?
You're throwing me off my stride.
As two clowns at the mercy of fate,
let's fight this out fair and square.
How goes the conspiracy you're
plotting with your friend?
What about you?
Have you accepted what Roswaal's doing?
There's only one thing
I value above all else.
There's no way that will ever change. Never.
So don't bother waiting
for me to change my mind.
Never say never.
Be quiet.
You're putting your hopes in Emilia-sama?
Yes, I am, and I believe in her.
Emilia-sama hasn't figured out
why she's been struggling.
Until she does, the same thing
will just keep happening.
We've already strayed from
what's written in the book.
Roswaal is free now!
She actually gave me advice...
Does she like me, too?
You're still talking like that?
If she hears you, she'll be furious.
Since Ram-san is working with the margrave,
doesn't that make you enemies?
Ram's my enemy?
Well, now I can see how
deeply you trust Ram-san.
And? What happened with
the margrave himself?
Everything's set.
The bet is officially on.
That's good to hear.
Of course, I don't think he's
ever lost at anything before,
so I had no doubt he would agree.
And next is...
Garfiel, yeah.
But first, can I just check into one thing?
All right. I'll continue with my
part of the plan as discussed.
And as for Emilia-sama...
That's one thing I can't
rely on your help with.
Or maybe I should say my own help...
I haven't even scratched the
surface of what's hurting her.
I guess I was just scared, after all.
That's for sure.
Don't try to play innocent.
Hey, man!
So are you prepared to scratch the
surface of what's hurting her?
Well, I'm prepared to ask her if I can.
Unlike Garfiel, I don't
have to worry about dying.
I'm not sure if I should
laugh at that or not.
Anyway, I guess you're one to take bets
that are stacked against you, huh?
I suppose so.
But taking on a bet without even
considering my odds of winning?
That's a first for me.
I thought I'd find you here, Ryuzu-san.
You talk like someone who already
knows me remarkably well.
I'd say you're right. I know
just about everything.
I even know what your goal is here.
Then I suppose the one Young Ros
was waiting for was you.
Yeah, sorry. That whole
thing's been called off.
Huh?
Anyway, I'm in the middle of a
huge face-off with Roswaal now.
I want it to end in a result
that's good for everyone,
which is why I want your help.
Why not use your Authority as an
apostle to demand my assistance?
I don't want to rely on
that kind of Authority.
I came here to talk to you.
Young men are so quick
to put on a tough front.
And? What is it you are arguing over?
In simple terms, I guess I'd say
a way to liberate the Sanctuary.
I know you're opposed to
liberating it, though.
I am opposed to liberating the Sanctuary?
Huh? Wait, you're not opposed to it?
Seriously?! You're kidding!
Then why did you...
Still, I cannot say that your
suspicions are entirely wild.
What is your opinion of Young Gar?
I think... there's no
avoiding a clash with him.
I see.
But...
But whether or not we can be friends
once that's over is yet to be seen.
And to help me make that decision,
I want to know more about him.
You are quite skilled at deceiving
the elderly, Young Su.
You asked the witch about me, did you not?
About the copies of Ryuzu Meyer,
and perhaps about the
purpose of creating them.
She told me about the immortality experiment
and that you Ryuzus were
the successful cases for it.
To this day, I protect and supervise
the crystal that creates the copies.
The four of us alternate in
bearing the role of supervisor.
I did hear about the "first four."
So the other three besides you...
My name is Natsuki Subaru.
What's your name, Ryuzu-san?
My name is Ryuzu Arma.
I am one of the first four copies.
Arma?
I am Ryuzu Bilma.
The first Ryuzu-san I met
called herself "Bilma."
I never meant to hide
anything from Ryuzu-san...
But why go through so much hassle?
Our bodies are not made of flesh and blood.
They are made of artificial
od clothed in mana.
All activity we engage in consumes the mana,
and continuous activity for
a full day is impossible.
Oh, so you're like the spirits.
That's why you've been alternating
between the four of you.
But... are you okay with that?
You are so kind, Young Su.
However, one of the first four,
Ryuzu Shima, is an exception.
Ryuzu Shima?
I will tell no one what you told me.
I swear it on the name of Ryuzu Shima.
About ten years ago, she caused a problem.
She was then removed from
the role of supervisor,
and now lives in the forest
with the other copies.
For that reason, three of us
fulfill the supervisor role now.
What problem did she cause?
She violated the contract with
the witch who created us
by entering the graveyard...
to bring back Young Gar
when he broke the rules to attempt
the trial and did not return.
I have not seen Shima since
she was stripped of her duty,
but it would be no surprise
if Young Gar has been meeting with Shima,
with whom he shares memories that we do not.
Memories that you three don't have?
I refer to the past that Young Gar
saw in the graveyard trial.
Are you aware of Young Gar's family situation?
Yeah, I know Frederica is his
sister from a different father,
and since she has less non-human blood,
she left the Sanctuary ten years ago.
Why did you leave the Sanctuary?
I suppose I wanted to create
an opportunity for the
people of the Sanctuary
to leave it once the barrier was broken.
I wanted to make a place for them.
At least, that's what she said.
Wait, did the past that Garfiel
saw involve the time she left?
No, what he saw was most likely
the moment when Young Gar
and Fred were left behind
by their mother when she left the Sanctuary.
That foolish, pitiful Garfiel
fears the outside world.
So the reason he's against
liberating the Sanctuary
is out of bitterness toward his mother for
abandoning him and choosing the outside?
The boy refers to himself as Garfiel Tinzel.
That is his mother's family name.
I believe he goes by that name
so that he won't forget her.
Whether it was out of anger or sadness
is most likely known only to him and Shima.
Emilia-tan?
Huh?
Subaru?
What're you doing down there, Emilia-tan?
You'll get your butt dirty.
Um... I'm a restless sleeper.
I'm sorry... I lied.
The truth is, I couldn't get to sleep.
But don't worry. I'll be sure to
get plenty of sleep by tonight.
It's almost noon, though.
You're talking about
sleeping until nightfall?
That's very slothful of you, Emilia-tan.
The way you said that...
just gives me a really weird feeling.
Really, Subaru, you're so mean.
Thank you.
Emilia, do you feel up to telling
me what you saw during the trial?
I won't claim that talking about
it will make you feel better.
But if you tell me, we can
worry about it together.
I don't know if I can be of any help...
but would you give me the right to
fight the same enemies you fight?
Subaru...
Subaru, you have so much faith in me...
The...
The past I saw...
was a memory from before
I went to sleep, I think.
I never told you that I was frozen
in ice for a long time, did I?
Frozen in... ice?
I was frozen in the forest for a long time.
Until Puck found me and got me out,
I had been sleeping within the
ice for a long, long time.
How long?
Since I was... six or
seven years old, maybe?
We all lived in the forest together
before it froze, I think.
You think?
I don't remember much from
before that happened.
What about your family?
My family wasn't in the forest.
But there was someone who
was like a mother to me...
Huh?
Wait, why...
My... mother?
Calm down. Take it slow.
What happened to all of them?
The same... as me.
They were frozen in ice.
I lived in the forest,
waiting with Puck for
all of them to wake up.
But that day never came.
So... I left the forest
and joined in the royal selection.
Huh?
What does the forest have to
do with the royal selection?
Roswaal promised me...
If you succeed in taking the throne,
perhaps I can thaw the ice
that encases this forest.
Does that make you think less of me?
All the other candidates are participating
with solid goals and resolutions,
but my reason is so, so personal.
Is that the "selfish reason"
you were talking about?
There's nothing bad about wanting
to save the people you care about.
Whether it's a lot of people or just
a few doesn't make it less noble.
Yeah...
Thank you... so much.
Emilia?
Do the memories that Emilia can't recall
hold some clue to getting through the trial?
Maybe Emilia can't remember,
but if I ask someone who does...
I'm sorry, Emilia.
Ow!
You didn't have to go that far, did you?!
Oh, I don't know...
Your love seems like the needy type,
so I'm a little scared to
let you stay beside Lia.
Should I erase you?
Don't say that like it's no big deal!
Anyway, Emilia-tan's really sad
since her family-member-slash-pet ran off.
I didn't exactly run off.
I've always been inside her.
It was good of you to call me, though.
That made me happy, Subaru.
Emilia!
Did you have another scary dream?
Puck?!
Thank goodness! Where have you been?
I was so worried!
Don't disappear like that again!
Puck?
Do I look a little smaller than usual?
I guess my limit came up
faster than I thought.
Of course, I was consciously
trying to break our contract,
so I guess it makes sense that I'd lose
my greatest strengths as a spirit.
Break... our contract?
Wh-What are you saying?
I've been by your side all this time.
I couldn't tell you only for
my own personal reasons,
and because of your own problems.
But from now on...
Huh?
No... What?! W-Wait, please!
Th-This is terrible, Puck!
The stone... The stone you reside in...
I'm sorry, Lia.
I wish I could explain everything,
but there's no time.
As much as it pains me,
I'm entrusting you to the one whose
love for you is second only to mine.
What... are you saying?
There's no one... There's no one who...
Lia...
I'm breaking the contract
between you and me.
I really am sorry this
turned out so one-sided.
Once I'm gone, the seal on
your memories will be lifted.
Remembering them will
probably make you very sad.
You might want to cry more
than you do right now.
Emilia...
I love you so, so much.
No...
Yes, that's good.
Lia...
I love you more than anyone in the world.
Emilia-sama fell unconscious?
Yeah, the spirit user's spirit left her.
If it drives her so nuts
that she misses the trial,
what good is she to us?
Do not say that.
This is a matter of the heart,
so it makes me sad for her.
Incidentally, Young Gar, about Young Su...
The dude who's covered in miasma?
Indeed. I do know what I said before,
but he does not appear to have
any connection with the witch.
I dunno about that.
Get yourself to bed, you doddering old hag.
"A rudy that stays up all night will
regret having short legs," ya know.
Emilia, are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm sure... I will be.
I want to believe I'll
be just fine by morning.
A-Anyway, just don't fret over it too much!
If there's anything I can do...
Well, I don't have much to offer,
but whatever I have is yours.
Emilia?
Hold my hand.
Will you stay here until morning?
If you do...
I think I can...
I'm sorry.
Please...
If this is what you want, that's easy.
Once it's morning... once
tomorrow comes, you'll be fine.
I believe in you.
Yeah.
Emilia!
I'm sorry, Emilia. I'm so sorry.
All the people who told you that kind lie,
that they wanted to protect you...
Please don't hate them.
Emilia, I love you so much.
Mother Fortuna, you liar.
Puck, you liar.
And Subaru... you liar.
Emilia-sama!
Did you find her?
No.
Emilia-sama!
Ram, what's goin' on here?
Garf...
Do you know where Emilia-sama went?
What?
Emilia-sama has disappeared.
We've all split up to search for her.
All right. I'll start lookin' around here.
Hey, old hag! You awake?
Someone might come by
lookin' for the princess.
You better go—
Old hag?! Old hag!
Somethin' doesn't feel right.
Old hag! You in here?!
Not here, either.
No way. Did they...
Old hag?!
I'm truly sorry to disappoint you...
But a friend asked for my help.
I realize it's only a small role,
but I've set out to play it.
You...
In truth, I had planned to talk
things over with you here.
Talk things over?
Yes, I wanted to talk to you with Ryuzu...
that is, with Shima-san in attendance.
But I really wasn't expecting
what happened with Emilia-sama.
That said, all kinds of conspiratorial
plans were already laid out.
So now that the host of the banquet is away,
how would you like to play the host instead?
...wanted to protect you...
I'm so sorry.
Please don't hate them.
Emilia...
All the people who told you that kind lie...
I'm sorry.
I love you so much.
Oh, good. I finally found you.
Subaru?
So, let's talk,
Emilia-tan.